(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
2023.03.15
BIRTHDAY LIVE
博衣こより
Hakui Koyori
ゲスト多数あり！
Featuring many guests!
博衣こより生誕祭LIVE 2023 Memories
Hakui Koyori Birthday LIVE 2023 Memories
乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.
Maiden, Seek Out the Q.E.D.
作詞・作曲・編曲：宮崎誠
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Miyazaki Makoto
Question! 知りたいな
Question! I want to know
君はさ 僕のこと
How do you...
どう思う？
...feel about me?
Question! 僕はね
Question! As for me...
君のこと...
...how I feel about you...
あとは宿題
...the rest is homework
ラブ・ラボ 引きこもっちゃうな
I'm cooped up in the Love Lab
聞かなきゃってほら愛称
Listen up, here's our nickname
（実験中）
(Under experiment)
論より証拠 主義です
Proof over argument is my policy
前進 あるのみ！
There's only moving forward!
ねぇ 少し手伝って
Hey, help me a little
人類の課題
With humanity's challenge
好き好き好き好き 好き好き好き好き
Like, like, like, like, like, like, like, like
答え合わせしましょう
Let's check our answers
見つけちゃう 魔法の公式
I'll find it, the magic formula
化学反応してるよね
We're having a chemical reaction, aren't we?
僕ら 問題は
As for us, the problem...
まだまだまだまだ 未解決
...is still, still, still unresolved
正解中 恋の予想
Calculating the correct love prediction
物理法則 書き足しちゃうもんね
I'll even add to the laws of physics
これぞ天才だ！
This is what a genius does!
あの子より
More than that girl
この子より
More than this girl
もっと「好き」って
Tell me you "like" me...
言ってちょうだい
...even more
乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.!!
Maiden, Seek Out the Q.E.D.!!
Question! やっぱりさ
Question! As I thought
さっきから僕のこと
You've been looking at me...
見てたよね？
...all this time, haven't you?
Question! 見てない？
Question! You weren't?
じゃあ...
Well then...
僕が君のこと...
...how I feel about you...
どきまぎ パラドックス
Flustered Paradox
慌てちゃって 隠れちゃう？
Should I panic and hide?
（葛藤中）
(In conflict)
宇宙も 秘密主義じゃ
If even the universe is secretive
ビッグバン！
Big Bang!
ねぇ 君とふたり
Hey, the two of us
人類の終わり
The end of humanity
好き好き好き好き 好き好き好き好き
Like, like, like, like, like, like, like, like
空前絶後でしょ？
It's unprecedented, right?
解きましょう 魔法の公式
Let's solve it, the magic formula
惹かれ合うたび 不思議なレポートは
Every time we're attracted, the mysterious report...
進行形
...is in progress
まだまだまだまだ 未提出
...and still, still, still unsubmitted
設計中 DNA
Designing DNA
君の細胞 書き換えちゃうもんね
I'll even rewrite your cells
ズバリ天才だ！
Truly a genius!
どの子より
More than any girl
この子より
More than this girl
ずっと「好き」って
I'm telling you I "like" you...
言ってるじゃん！
...forever!
乙女よ急げよQ.E.D.!!
Maiden, Hurry Up the Q.E.D.!!
ねぇ 僕らふたり
Hey, the two of us
人類の終わりに
At the end of humanity
割り切れなかった
What couldn't be divided...
あまりだったら
...if there's a remainder...
ねぇ 少し手伝って
Hey, help me a little
人類の課題
With humanity's challenge
好き好き好き好き 好き好き好き好き
Like, like, like, like, like, like, like, like
答え合わせしましょう
Let's check our answers
見つけちゃう 魔法の公式
I'll find it, the magic formula
化学反応してるよね
We're having a chemical reaction, aren't we?
僕ら 問題は
As for us, the problem...
まだまだまだまだ 未解決
...is still, still, still unresolved
正解中 恋の予想
Calculating the correct love prediction
物理法則 書き足しちゃうもんね
I'll even add to the laws of physics
これぞ天才だ！
This is what a genius does!
最短 あの子より
Fastest, more than that girl
その子より
more than that girl
もっと「好き」って言ってちょうだい
Please say "I love you" more
乙女よ求めよ
Oh maidens, seek...
Q.E.D.!!
3.1415
92653589793238
46264338327
Q.E.D.!!
はーい！皆さん！こんこよー！
Hi everyone! Konkoyo!
ホロライブ6期生、秘密結社holoXの
Hololive 6th gen, Secret Society holoX's...
頭脳！博衣こよりだよー！
Brain! It's Hakui Koyori!
今日は、こよの生誕ライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to Koyori's birthday live today!
お誕生日おめでとうのコメントもいっぱいありがとー！
Thank you for all the "Happy Birthday" comments too!
まず1曲目は、1周年でお披露目した七星管弦楽団さんに作っていただいた
First up, the first song was an original song created by Nanahoshi Orchestra, which I premiered at my 1st anniversary...
オリジナル曲「乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.」から始めさせていただきました！
...called "Otome yo Motome yo Q.E.D."!
ダンスも、みんな、この曲どうでしたか？
How was the song and dance, everyone?
そして、見てください！ジャジャーン！
And, look at this! Ta-da!
今回ライブ用にめちゃめちゃ可愛いステージを作っちゃいました！
I've created an incredibly cute stage just for this live!
お誕生日ケーキもドドンとありますし、
There's a big birthday cake...
なんと、こよの大好きなドットも使っていたりして、めちゃめちゃ素敵じゃないですか？
...and I'm even using pixel art, which I love! Isn't it wonderful?
さて、このステージで行う今回のライブは、サブタイトルに「Memories」と付いているように、
Now, this live on this stage, as the subtitle "Memories" suggests...
デビューしてから今日までの思い出の一部を曲と一緒に振り返るというテーマで作りました。
...was created with the theme of looking back at some of my memories from my debut until today, together with songs.
こよと皆さんとの思い出、そしてゲストの皆さんとの思い出、
Memories of me and everyone, and memories with the guests...
歌と演出とでたくさん詰め込みましたので、ぜひ最後の瞬間まで見ていってくださいね！
...I've packed them all into the songs and performance, so please watch until the very last moment!
それでは、ゲストパート1発目！早速いっちゃおー！
Now then, the first guest part! Let's get right into it!
2022年にこの作品と出会えた思い出とともに、
Along with the memory of encountering this work in 2022...
大好きな先輩とアイドルしちゃいます！
I'm going to be an idol with my favorite seniors!
START:DASH!!
作詞: 畑 亜貴 / 作曲: 藤田淳平(Elements Garden)
編曲: 藤田淳平(Elements Garden)
START:DASH!!
Lyrics: Aki Hata / Composition: Junpei Fujita (Elements Garden)
Arrangement: Junpei Fujita (Elements Garden)
産毛の小鳥たちも
Even the fledglings...
いつか空に羽ばたく
will one day take wing into the sky.
大きな強い翼で
With big, strong wings...
飛ぶ
they'll fly.
諦めちゃだめなんだ
You must not give up.
その日が絶対来る
That day will surely come.
君も感じてるよね
You feel it too, don't you?
始まりの鼓動
The heartbeat of a beginning.
明日よ変われ！
Change, tomorrow!
希望に変われ！
Change into hope!
眩しい光に
In the dazzling light...
照らされて変われ
be illuminated and change.
START!!
悲しみに閉ざされて
Shut in by sadness...
泣くだけの君じゃない
you're not someone who just cries.
熱い胸 きっと未来を
With a burning heart, surely the future...
切り拓くはずさ
you'll surely carve it out.
悲しみに閉ざされて
Shut in by sadness...
泣くだけじゃつまらない
it's boring to just cry.
きっと
Surely...
君の夢の力
the power of your dreams...
いまを動かす力
the power to move the present...
信じてるよ… だから START!!
I believe in it... so START!!
雨上がりの気分で
With a post-rain feeling...
高まる期待の中
in the midst of rising expectations...
つまずいたことさえも
even the things we tripped over...
思い出にしよう
let's make them memories.
明日が咲くよ！
Tomorrow will bloom!
希望が咲くよ！
Hope will bloom!
たのしいメロディ
A fun melody...
口ずさみ咲いた
hummed it, and it bloomed.
DASH!!
喜びを受けとめて
Embrace the joy...
君と僕つながろう
let's connect, you and I.
迷い道やっと外へ
Finally out of the maze...
抜け出したはずさ
we should have escaped.
喜びを受けとめて
Embrace the joy...
君と僕進むだろう
we will move forward, you and I.
それは
That is...
…かけらだけど
...fragments, but
愛しいかけら
precious fragments.
君と僕と
You and me...
START:DASH!!
またひとつ 夢が生まれて
Another dream is born.
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
悲しみに閉ざされて
Trapped in sadness,
泣くだけの君じゃない
you're not just someone who cries.
熱い胸 きっと未来を
A passionate heart will surely
切り拓くはずさ
pave the way to the future.
喜びを受け止めて
Accept the joy.
君と僕 つながろう
Let's connect, you and I.
迷い道 やっと外へ
We must have finally found our way
抜け出したはずさ
out of the maze.
喜びを受け止めて
Accept the joy.
君と僕 進むだろう
You and I will move forward.
それは
That is
遠い
a distant
夢のかけら
fragment of a dream.
だけど
But
愛しいかけら
it's a precious fragment.
君と僕と
You and me...
START:DASH!!
ヘイ！ヘイ！ヘイ！ START:DASH!!
Hey! Hey! Hey! START:DASH!!
一緒にお風呂に入ったり
Taking a bath together,
ASMRをしたり…
doing ASMR...
てぇてぇさせていただいた思い出と共に、歌います！
I'll sing with the 'te-te-y' memories we shared!
可愛くてごめん
Kawaikute Gomen
私が私のこと愛して
What's wrong with me
何が悪いの？ 嫉妬でしょうか？
loving myself? Is it jealousy?
痛いとか変わってるとか
Saying it's painful or weird...
届きませんね そのリプライ
those replies don't reach me.
大好きな服
My favorite clothes.
大好きなメイクで
With my favorite makeup.
お決まりのハーフツイン巻いて
Curling my usual half-twin tails.
お出かけしよ 日傘持って
Let's go out, with a parasol,
紅茶飲んで 幸せだもん
drinking tea, because I'm happy.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born.
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being calculatingly cute.
気になっちゃうよね？ ごめん
You're curious, aren't you? Sorry.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for putting in the effort.
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious.
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for my high femininity.
ムカついちゃうよね？ ざまぁｗ
It's annoying, isn't it? Serves you right! lol
貴方は貴方のことだけ
Please just worry about yourself
どうぞ私に干渉しないでください
and don't interfere with me.
類は友を呼ぶと言うけど
They say birds of a feather flock together,
届きませんね その陰口
but those whispers don't reach me.
重い厚底ブーツ
Heavy platform boots.
お気に入りのリュックで
With my favorite backpack.
崩せない前髪 櫛でといて
Combing my bangs that I can't mess up.
お出かけしよ 軽い女
Let's go out. 'Easy woman'?
ふざけんな 重すぎるわ
Don't mess with me, I'm way too heavy.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
この時代生きてごめん
Sorry for living in this era.
Chu! 目立っててごめん
Chu! Sorry for standing out.
意識しちゃうよね？ ごめん
You can't help but notice, right? Sorry.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
自分磨きしてごめん
Sorry for improving myself.
Chu! ぶりっ子でごめん
Chu! Sorry for acting like a cutesy girl.
虜にしちゃってごめん
Sorry for making you my captive.
ムカついちゃうでしょ？ ざまぁｗ
You're annoyed, aren't you? Serves you right! lol
趣味の違い 変わり者とかにされても
Even if I'm called a weirdo for having different tastes.
曲げたくない 怖くもない
I don't want to change. I'm not afraid
あんたらごとき
of the likes of you.
自分の味方は自分でありたい
I want to be my own ally.
一番大切にしてあげたい
I want to treasure myself the most.
理不尽な我慢はさせたくない
I don't want to force myself to endure
それが私
unreasonable things. That's who I am.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
Chu! 生まれてきちゃってごめん
Chu! Sorry for being born.
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being calculatingly cute.
可愛くてごめん
Sorry for being cute
楽しんでごめん
Sorry for having fun
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for working so hard
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for being so feminine
ムカついちゃうよね？ざまぁ
It's annoying, isn't it? Serves you right
次に、歌います！
Next, we will sing!
路地裏の真ん中で慣れない景色と
In the middle of the back alley, with unfamiliar scenery
好かない匂いに私は覆われて
And smells I don't like, I'm covered
染まっていくんでしょう
And I'll be dyed by them, right?
ヨワネハキ
Yowanehaki
私は怖がりで知らないことには手を付けず
I'm a coward, I don't touch things I don't know
誰かがやって来て毒味をするまで待っていた
I waited until someone came and tasted it for poison
することは単純でマニュアル通りの生活を
The things I do are simple, a manual-like life
来る日も淡々と過ごしていた
Spending every day indifferently
そいやさそいやさ 昨日の私もこうだった
Heave-ho, heave-ho, I was like this yesterday too
そいやさそいやさ
Heave-ho, heave-ho
弱音を吐いている 薄っぺらい人間です
I'm a shallow person who whines
一歩前に出るのはやめておきます
I'll refrain from taking a step forward
絡まれたくはないからさ
Because I don't want to be involved
描いた理想像に現実味がないから
Because the ideal image I drew isn't realistic
近づけないように生きておきます
I'll live so as not to get close
明日も同じをさしておきます
I'll stick to the same thing tomorrow too
路地裏の真ん中でいつもの夕日を薄めて眺めて
In the middle of the back alley, thinning and watching the usual sunset
胸の中で呟いた いつまで続くんだろう
I muttered in my heart, how long will this last?
そいやさそいやさ 昨日の夕飯これだった
Heave-ho, heave-ho, this was yesterday's dinner
そいやさそいやさ
Heave-ho, heave-ho
臆病でキリがない 意気地なし人間です
I'm a cowardly person with no end to my fears
一歩後ろに下がって逃げておきます
I'll take a step back and run away
目立ちたくなんかないからさ
Because I don't want to stand out at all
描いた理想像に現実味がないから
Because the ideal image I drew isn't realistic
近づけないように生きておきます
I'll live so as not to get close
明日も同じをさしておきます
I'll stick to the same thing tomorrow too
弱音を吐いている 薄っぺらい人間です
I'm a shallow person who whines
一歩前に出るのはやめておきます
I'll refrain from taking a step forward
絡まれたくはないからさ
Because I don't want to be involved
溜め息ばかりさ 吸う息足りないの
Nothing but sighs, not enough breath to inhale
きっとそう上手くはいかないけどさ
I'm sure it won't go that well, but
試しにちゃんと生きてみよう
Let's try to live properly as a test
何度も解散しました
We disbanded many times
訳が分からないよ
I don't understand why
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made
コネクト
Connect
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes and confirm it
押し寄せた闇 振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the encroaching darkness and move forward
いつになったらなくした未来を
When will I be able to see the lost future
私ここでまた見ることできるの？
Again here?
溢れ出した不安の影も
Even the shadows of overflowing anxiety
何度でも裂いてこの世界歩んでいこう
I'll tear through them again and again and walk this world
とめどなく刻まれた時は今始まりを告げ
The relentlessly carved time now heralds the beginning
変わらない思いをのせ
Carrying unchanging feelings
閉ざされた扉開けよう
Let's open the closed door
コネクト
Connect
目覚めた心は走り出した 未来を描くため
My awakened heart started running to paint the future.
難しい道で立ち止まっても 空はきれいな青さで
Even if I stop on a difficult path, the sky is a beautiful blue...
いつも待っててくれるから怖くない
...always waiting for me, so I'm not afraid.
もう何があっても挫けない
No matter what happens, I won't give up.
解散だー！！
Disband!!
ふり返れば仲間がいて
When I look back, my friends are there.
気がつけば優しく包まれてた
Before I knew it, I was gently enveloped.
何もかもが歪んだ世界で
In a world where everything is distorted,
唯一信じれるここが救いだった
The only thing I can believe in, this place, was my salvation.
喜びも悲しみも
Both joy and sadness,
分け合えば強まる想い
If we share them, our feelings will grow stronger.
この声が届くのなら
If this voice reaches you,
きっと奇跡は起こせるだろう
Surely we can make a miracle happen.
交わした約束忘れないよ 目を閉じ確かめる
I won't forget the promise we made; I close my eyes and confirm it.
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the encroaching darkness and move forward.
どんなに大きな壁があっても
No matter how big the wall is,
越えてみせるからきっと
I'll show you I can overcome it, for sure.
明日信じて祈って
Believing in tomorrow, I pray.
壊れた世界で彷徨って私は
Wandering in a broken world, I...
引き寄せられるように辿り着いた
...arrived as if drawn towards it.
目覚めた心は走り出した
My awakened heart started running...
未来を描くため難しい道で
...to paint the future, even on a difficult path.
立ち止まっても空はきれいな青さで
Even if I stop, the sky is a beautiful blue...
いつも待っててくれるから怖くない
...always waiting for me, so I'm not afraid.
もう何があっても挫けない
No matter what happens, I won't give up.
ずっと明日待って
Always waiting for tomorrow.
あぁ楽しもうよシーソー
Ah, let's enjoy the seesaw.
揺らす度受け取った不安定な
Every time it sways, I received an unstable...
居場所が浮くんだ
...place that floats up.
エゴイスティック・シーソー
Egoistic Seesaw
知らない事ばかり
Only things I didn't know.
起き過ぎたね目まぐるしく
Too many things happened in a dizzying whirl.
生きてたらそれはそれで当然か
I guess that's natural when you're alive.
当たりの入ってない運試し
A test of luck with no winning lot.
叫んで唇を噛んで全てひっくり返したい
I want to scream, bite my lip, and turn everything upside down.
せっかくだし事後報告でエゴイスティックに
Since I'm at it, I'll be egoistic and report after the fact.
騒ぎすぎ限界で痛いなら
If it hurts because I've made too much noise at my limit...
労って世界までの正体頂戴
...then reward me and give me the true identity of the world.
あぁ楽しもうよシーソー
Ah, let's enjoy the seesaw.
揺らす度受け取った不安定な
Every time it sways, I received an unstable...
居場所が浮くんだ
...place that floats up.
落ちた傷は舐めてじゃれたら
If I lick my fallen wounds and play around...
後悔のないよう最後まで生き急ごう
...let's live life to the fullest until the end without regrets.
値札の付いてない僕らのゲーム
Our game with no price tag.
抗って来たけれど 僕等のゲーム
We've been fighting back, but in our game
今は今で大変か
is it tough right now?
模範にならない この遊び方
This way of playing that doesn't follow any model
飽きず報われるなんて 考えず無邪気に
Thinking of being rewarded without getting bored, innocently
結局ただ笑えたなら それでよかった
In the end, as long as we could laugh, that was enough
ずっと察せない鈍感さ拾ったら
If I pick up an insensitivity that I'll never notice
クラクラしちゃいそう はしゃいでしまおう
I feel like I'm going dizzy, let's just make some noise
たまに見かける進化を追って
Chasing the evolution I occasionally see
急ぎ転れば尻尾挟む
If I hurry and fall, I'll tuck my tail
委ねられないラインを 無我夢中で
Crossing the line I can't leave to others, frantically
超えて前へ 理想への
forward, towards the ideal
招待 頂戴 一生
Give me an invitation, for life
ああ楽しもうよ シーソー 壊すほど目一杯
Ah, let's enjoy the seesaw as much as possible until it breaks
戯れて居場所自分勝手
Frolicking in my own selfish place
落ちた傷は日常なんでしょ
the fallen wounds are just daily life, right?
後悔のないよう 最後まで生き急ごう
Let's rush through life to the end so we have no regrets
やりたいこと成して楽しい
It's fun to accomplish what you want to do
手を振ってらしくいたい 苦しいなんて嫌だ
Waving my hand, I want to be myself, I hate being in pain
真っ直ぐなりふり構わず
Straight ahead, regardless of appearances
網羅したい 我儘な夢もっと
I want to encompass more of my selfish dreams
謳歌しよう
Let's celebrate
はい、ということで
Yes, so
怒涛のゲストコーナーからソロ曲でしたー！
After the whirlwind guest corner, that was a solo song!
みんな、「何の曲？」ってなってたね！
Everyone was like, "What song is this?"
実はこの曲は、こよからのサプライズプレゼントです！
Actually, this song is a surprise present from Koyo!
今の曲はなんと、4曲目のオリジナル曲なんですよ！ イエーイ！
That song was actually my 4th original song! Yay!
昨日の誕生日カウントダウン配信で
In the birthday countdown stream yesterday,
3曲目のオリジナル曲も発表しているので
I also announced my 3rd original song,
まさかもう1曲あるとは思ってなかったんじゃないですか？
so I bet you didn't think there would be one more, right? Hehehe.
実はこの曲は、先ほどクロたんと一緒に歌った
Actually, this song was written by Sho Watanabe,
「コネクト」も作っていらっしゃる渡辺翔さんに作っていただきました！
who also wrote "Connect" which I just sang with Kuro-tan!
今までの楽曲とガラッと変えて
It's a completely different style from my previous songs,
魂を削って歌うような熱いエモい曲にしていただきました！
an emotional song that feels like I'm singing with my soul!
この曲「エゴイスティック・シーソー」は
For this song "Egoistic Seesaw,"
なんとこのライブの後すぐにMVがプレミア公開！
the MV will be premiered right after this live!
そして本日3月15日の24時、3月16日の0時から
And today, March 15th at 24:00, March 16th at 0:00,
デジタル販売がスタートいたします！
digital sales will start!
概要欄にもURLとか追加しますので、ぜひチェックしてくださいね！
I'll add the URL and other info to the description box, so please check it out!
それでは！ この後はまだまだ怒涛のライブコーナーです！
Now then! After this, the whirlwind live corner continues!
2つ目のゲストパートもありますので、楽しんでいってください！
There's also a second guest part, so please look forward to it!
それでは、ステージを移動しまーす！ 行くよー！
Now, moving to the stage! Here we go!
時を刻む唄 作曲・作詞：麻枝准
Song of Time's Ticking
Composition/Lyrics: Jun Maeda
落ちていく砂時計ばかり見てるよ
I'm only watching the falling hourglass
さかさまにすれば ほらまた始まるよ
If you turn it upside down, look, it starts again
刻んだだけ進む時間に
In the time that moves forward as it ticks
いつか僕も入れるかな
I wonder if I can enter it someday too
きみだけが過ぎ去った坂の途中は
On the middle of the hill where only you passed by
あたたかな日だまりがいくつもできてた
Many warm sunny spots had formed
僕ひとりがここで優しい
I am here alone, remembering
温かさを思い返してる
that gentle warmth
きみだけを
Only you
好きでいたよ
I was in love with
風で目が滲んで
My eyes blur from the wind
遠くなるよ
and you become distant
Will become distant
いつまでも 覚えてる
I'll remember forever
なにもかも 変わっても
Even if everything changes
ひとつだけ ひとつだけ
Just one thing, just one thing
ありふれた ものだけど
Though it's something ordinary
見せてやる
I will show you
輝きに満ちた そのひとつだけ
That one thing filled with radiance
いつまでも いつまでも
Forever and ever
守ってゆく
I'll protect it
肌寒い日が続く もう春なのに
Chilly days continue, even though it's already spring
目覚まし時計より早く起きた朝
The morning I woke up earlier than the alarm clock
三人分の朝ご飯を作るきみが
You, making breakfast for three
そこに立っている
Are standing right there
きみだけが
Only you
そばにいないよ
Are not by my side
昨日まで
Until yesterday
すぐそばで
Right beside me
僕を見てたよ
You were looking at me
きみだけを
Only you
好きでいたよ
I have loved
きみだけと
Only with you
歌う唄だよ
Is the song I sing
僕たちの
Our
刻んだ時だよ
Is the time we've carved
片方だけ
Only for one of us
続くなんて
To continue
僕は嫌だよ
I hate it
いつまでも 覚えてる
I'll remember forever
この町が 変わっても
Even if this town changes
どれだけの 悲しみと
No matter how much sadness
出会うことになっても
I might encounter
見せてやる 本当は
I will show you how strong
強かったときのこと
I actually was at that time
さあいくよ 歩き出す
Come on, I'm starting to walk
坂の道を
Up the slope
がんばれ!
Do your best!
下手っぴだけど、立ち向かう。
I'm a novice, but I'll face it.
たくさんのゲームから、諦めない心を学びました。
I learned a never-give-up spirit from many games.
嗚呼、いつもの様に過ぎる日々に あくびが出る
Ah, I yawn at the days passing by as usual
さんざめく夜、越え、今日も渋谷の街に朝が降る
Crossing the noisy night, morning falls on Shibuya again today
どこか虚しいような そんな気持ち つまらないな
A somewhat empty feeling like that, it's boring
でもそれでいい そんなもんさ これでいい
But that's fine, that's how it is, this is fine
知らず知らず隠してた
Ring out the true voice
本当の声を響かせてよ ほら
You've been hiding unconsciously, see
見ないふりしていても
Even if you pretend not to see it
確かにそこにある
It's certainly there
感じたままに描く 自分で選んだその色で
Paint as you feel, with the colors you chose yourself
眠い空気纏う朝に
The blue world that arrived
訪れた青い世界
In the morning draped in a sleepy atmosphere
好きなものを「好き」だと言う
Saying you "like" what you like
怖くて仕方ないけど
I'm scared out of my wits, but
本当の自分、出会えた気がしたんだ
I felt like I could meet my true self
嗚呼、手を伸ばせば
Ah, if I reach out my hand
伸ばすほどに
The more I reach out
遠くへゆく
The further away it goes
思うようにいかない、今日も
Things don't go as I want, even today
また慌ただしくもがいてる
I'm struggling hectically again
悔しい気持ちもただ情けなくて
Even these frustrating feelings are just miserable
涙が出る
And the tears fall
踏み込むほど
The more I step into it
苦しくなる
The more painful it becomes
痛くもなる
And it starts to hurt too
嗚呼、感じたままに進む
Ah, I move forward as I feel
自分で選んだこの道を
Along this path that I chose myself
重いまぶた擦る night に
On nights when I rub my heavy eyelids
しがみついた青い誓い
I clung to that blue vow
好きなことを続けること
Continuing to do what I love
それは「楽しい」だけじゃない
It's not just "fun"
本当にできる？
“Can I really do it?”
不安になるけど
I get anxious, but...
何枚でも　ほら何枚でも
No matter how many pages, look, no matter how many
自信がないから描いてきたんだよ
Because I lack confidence, I've kept drawing
何回でも　ほら何回でも
No matter how many times, look, no matter how many
積み上げてきたことが武器になる
Everything I've built up will become my weapon
周りを見たって　誰と比べたって
No matter how much I look around, no matter who I compare myself to
僕にしかできないことはなんだ
What is it that only I can do?
今でも自信なんかない
Even now, I have no confidence
それでも
Even so
感じたことない気持ち
Feelings I've never felt before
知らずにいた想い
Emotions I never knew
あの日踏み出して、初めて
Stepping out that day, for the first time
感じたこの痛みも全部
All this pain I felt, too
好きなものと向き合うことで
By facing the things I love
触れたまだ小さな光
I touched a light that's still small
大丈夫、行こう
It's okay, let's go
あとは楽しむだけだ
All that's left is to enjoy it
嗚呼、全てを賭けて描く
Ah, I'll draw, risking everything
自分にしか出せない色で
With colors that only I can produce
朝も夜も走り続け
Keep running, morning and night
見つけ出した青い光
I found that blue light
好きなものと向き合うこと
Facing the things you love
今だって怖いことだけど
Is still a scary thing even now
もう今は　あの日の透明な僕じゃない
But I'm no longer the transparent me from that day
ありのままの　かけがえの無い僕だ
I am my true, irreplaceable self
知らず知らず隠してた
I was hiding it without even knowing
本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
Let your true voice ring out, look
見ないふりしていても
Even if you pretend not to see it
確かにそこに今もそこにあるよ
It's definitely there, it's still there now
知らず知らず隠してた
I was hiding it without even knowing
本当の声を響かせてよ、さあ
Let your true voice ring out, come on
見ないふりしていても
Even if you pretend not to see it
確かにそこに君の中に
It's definitely there, inside of you
トワ様とこより、まさかの同期？！
Towa-sama and Koyori, unexpected genmates?!
1年で本当にマブになれた！
We really became best friends in one year!
と勝手に思っています。ぜひ
Or so I like to think. Please...
風に吹かれて
Blown by the wind
誰も気づかぬよう
So that no one notices
区別がつかない
Unable to distinguish
モノクロの世界
A monochrome world
色を足しても
Even if I add colors
何も見えなくて
I can't see anything
まるで私は
It's as if I...
息を止めていた
...had stopped breathing
もういいよ
It's okay now
遠くても叶えたい
Even if it's far away, I want it to come true
私は
I...
こんな世界想いも抱きしめていたいのに
I want to hold onto these feelings and this world, and yet...
夢のキャンバスに
On the canvas of my dreams
居続ける意味は
The meaning of continuing to be here
この胸に輝いているストーリー
Is the story shining in my heart
与えることに
In giving...
意味などないけど
...there is no meaning, but
拾い集めた
Having gathered them up
カケラ失うの？
Will I lose these fragments?
そして夜は
And the night...
その冷たさを
...will melt that coldness
溶かして手を伸ばした
And I reached out my hand
もういいよ
It's okay now
遠くても届けたい
Even if it's far away, I want to reach you
私は
I...
受け止めてく
I'll accept it
涙も 抱きしめていたいのに
Even though I want to embrace the tears too
夢のキャンパスに 心込めるのは
Putting my heart into the dream's canvas
この空に描きだして
Start drawing in this sky
ストーリー
Story
ドッキリ大成功☆
Prank Successful☆
逆ドッキリが成功した瞬間は気持ちよかった。
The moment the reverse prank succeeded felt great.
トラップを仕掛け合った3人で歌います。
The three of us who set traps for each other will now sing.
いつだって君を ずっと見ていたわけじゃない
It's not like I've been watching you all the time
僕の考えを 当ててごらんよ
Try to guess what I'm thinking
ささいなしぐさ 視線まばたき
Slight gestures, glances, and blinks
君をもう手のひらに
I've already got you in the palm of my hand
剥き出しのトラップなんて かかるわけないわ
There's no way I'd fall for such an obvious trap
甘い言葉にも惑わされない
I won't be misled by sweet words
かからない かからないふりして
I won't fall for it, pretending not to fall for it
見透かしちゃうよ
I'll see right through you
Looking Thinking Touching Feeling Why You Know?
Looking Thinking Touching Feeling I'm In
Looking Thinking Touching Feeling Understand
Meaning Meaning of Love Are you ready?
自覚なきでしょ ねえ思い通りに
You're not aware, are you? Just as I planned
君は動かされていること
That you're being manipulated
単純じゃないの 駆け引きのヒント
It's not simple, the hints for the strategy
全てに隠された意味を
The meaning hidden in everything
意味を 意味を 追求してく
The meaning, the meaning, I'll pursue it
意味を 意味を 二人のこと
The meaning, the meaning, about us two
意味を 意味を 親密にしましょう
The meaning, the meaning, let's become intimate
秘密のステージへ
To the secret stage
その眼 その瞳に私はどう映るの
How do I look in those eyes, in those pupils?
とてもきらびやかで まるでシンデレラ
So radiant, just like Cinderella
突き刺さる視線 好きと感じて
Piercing gazes, feeling the love
君に余裕見せつけちゃって
I'll show you my composure
あとのまつりで 見返してあきあきしちゃうよ
It's too late now, looking back and getting tired of it
すでに君はもう出来上がってる
You're already all set up
頭の次の 次の次まで
To the next, and the next after that, in your mind
見透かさなくちゃ
I have to see through it
Looking Thinking Touching Feeling Why You Know?
Looking Thinking Touching Feeling I'm In
Looking Thinking Touching Feeling Understand
Meaning Meaning of Love Are you ready?
唯一無二のジョーカー 手にするために
To get your hands on the one and only Joker
四苦八苦さらけ出してる方
The one who's revealing their struggles
離れていく世界の中枢を
The center of the world that's drifting away
君は楽しめる？
Can you enjoy it?
意味を 意味を 求めていくわ
The meaning, the meaning, I'll go seeking it
意味を 意味を 完璧にしてね
The meaning, the meaning, make it perfect
意味を 意味を 後戻りは
The meaning, the meaning, there's no going back
できないステージへ
To the stage we can't return from
気が付いてるでしょう？ ここにいる意味さえも
You've noticed it, haven't you? Even the meaning of being here.
切り札はそれぞれ 互いの手札に
The trump cards are respectively in each other's hands.
はなから心で暴き出して
Exposing it from the heart from the very beginning,
胸を撃ち抜け
Shoot through the chest.
自覚ないでしょうね
You probably don't realize it,
思い通りに君は動かされていること
That you're being moved exactly as intended.
単純じゃないの 駆け引きのヒントを
It's not simple. Picking up all the hints of the bargaining,
すべて拾って
Picking up everything.
唯一無二のジョーカーにしてみせることで
By turning you into the one and only Joker,
理解できた愛のカタチを
The shape of love that I've come to understand.
いつかの誰かに仕組まれていても
Even if it was set up by someone once upon a time,
最後に笑う君と
With you who laughs last.
ミリオン 加速してゆく
Million, accelerating.
ミリオン ミリオン あらわなコトバ
Million, Million, exposed words.
ミリオン ミリオン 深層は次のステージへ
Million, Million, the deep layers go to the next stage.
おつぼね宝鐘先輩と新人博衣さん。
Senior Marine Houshou and Rookie Hakui.
マリン先輩自作ゲーム『セカワ』のプレイなど、
Playing Marine-senpai's self-made game "Sekawa," and more...
たくさんの思い出とともに、頭ピンク組の二人で歌います！
Along with many memories, the "Pink-Haired Duo" will sing!
魅惑を込める箱
A box filled with charm.
秘宝に香る
Fragrant with hidden treasure,
危なげな
Dangerous.
DANGEROUS! 頭ピンク組！
DANGEROUS! The Pink-Haired Duo!
あほーい！ これ開けたら君たちに何してあげるべきかな？
Ahoy! What should I do for you all once this is opened?
探してたのは船長？ う～ん…はぁん
Was it the Captain you were looking for? Mm... haan...
そんなにガッツいちゃダメだぞっ…かな？
You shouldn't be so greedy... I think?
お宝よりも魅力的なもの、見つけちゃった。いいじゃない！
I found something even more charming than treasure. Isn't it great!
左右が寝取られた
Left and right were taken,
極上の海賊の秘宝、
The finest pirate's treasure,
それは私。
That would be me.
艶やかに漂う、
Floating glamorously,
香りを高く
With a rich fragrance.
抗わないで、
Don't resist,
開けてみて。
Try opening it.
SEXY 世界一 SUPER ぴちぴち
SEXY World number one, SUPER perky.
ぶっちゃけ船長捕まえたい
Honestly, I want to catch the Captain.
YOU BETTER GET THE TREASURE Merry destiny
私の甘さじゃ欲しいでしょ？
You want my sweetness, don't you?
AHOY! 秘宝の鍵は
AHOY! The key to the secret treasure is,
AHOY! 優しく差し込んで
AHOY! Insert it gently.
AHOY! 重厚な扉
AHOY! The heavy door...
あ、あ、あ、マジではしたない！
Ah, ah, ah, that's really improper!
あほーい！
Ahoy!
震えてた貴方の手
Your hands were trembling.
海図にこぼす甘いため息のティー
The sweet sigh tea spilled on the nautical chart.
ジャンクの薔薇が 添えられる前に
Before a junk rose is added.
VIVI Sensation Sexy
七つの大海を
Through the seven seas,
探し回りに
Searching high and low,
駆け進め
Run full speed ahead!
Shiny Ocean Marine
まだ手探りね、
Still fumbling, aren't you?
何想像してんの？
What are you imagining?
Now please grab my dress
PLEASE OPEN AT THIS BOX
PLEASE OPEN THIS BOX
OPEN! IT'S LIKE LOVE
I WILL SCREAM
あ！ ああ！！ 開けろー！！！
Ah! Ahh!! Open it!!!
Just maybe love me
私のすべてを手に入れて
Get your hands on all of me
Ah!
キミの財宝
Your treasure
ハシタナイでしょ
It's shameless, isn't it?
シアワセに鳴っちゃう
I'll start singing with happiness
誰か助けて
Someone, help me!
マジで遠慮しすぎ
Seriously, you're being too reserved
キミたち何考えてんの！
What are you guys thinking!
分かってるのは渇望
What I know is craving
だから今すぐ開けてよ
So open it right now
宝箱
Treasure box
あなたを待ってるんです
I'm waiting for you
あけて！
Open it!
たくさんの思い出を巡るライブ、楽しんでいただけていますかー？
Are you all enjoying this live performance that goes through many memories?
たくさんのパチパチパチもありがとー！
Thank you for all the clapping too!
でもですね、思い出を振り返っているだけでは先へは進めません！
But you know, we can't move forward just by looking back at memories!
思い出とともに、もっともっと素敵な未来へ歩んでいけるように、
So that we can walk towards an even more wonderful future along with our memories,
今日発表したばかりの3曲目のオリジナル曲を歌って踊らせてください！
Please let me sing and dance to my 3rd original song, which I just announced today!
博衣こよりの自己紹介ソングです！
It's Hakui Koyori's self-introduction song!
いくよ！史上最大のQUESTION!
Here we go! The Greatest QUESTION in History!
今（ゼッタイ）以上（史上）最大　叶えましょう！
Let's make it the greatest (historical) maximum, more than (absolutely) now!
こんこよー！博衣こよりだよー！
Konkoyo! I'm Hakui Koyori!
今日は人類最大の難問を証明していくよ！
Today I'm going to prove humanity's greatest difficult problem!
探究心メラメラ抑えられないのです
I can't suppress my burning curiosity
冷えこよなんぞ余裕です
Hiekoyo is a piece of cake
声はぴろーです！ずのー！
My voice is pillow-like! Brain!
またひとつ発見　マヨネーズは飲み物です
Another discovery: Mayonnaise is a drink
カモン Q and A
Come on, Q and A
あっち　こっち　ほら巻き起こる
Over there, over here, look, a drama unfolds,
ドラマに体当たり…実験！
diving in headfirst... Experiment!
感じてみなきゃ始まらない
It won't start if you don't try to feel it
研究！生成！余裕で Are you OK?
Research! Creation! Easily, are you OK?
一緒にどんどん過ごしましょう
Let's spend more and more time together
あなたと経験していきたい
I want to experience things with you
全部の夢そろえて証明完了ーQ.E.D.ー
Gather all our dreams, proof complete -Q.E.D.-
したってね　また次がある
Even so, there's always a next one
泣いて　笑って　わおーん
Crying, laughing, wa-on
どんな日も永遠　願いはスマイル
Any day is eternal, my wish is a smile
その胸に芽生えて欲しいシアワセ
I want happiness to sprout in your heart
今（ゼッタイ）以上（史上）最大　叶えましょう！
Let's make it the greatest (historical) maximum, more than (absolutely) now!
助手くんたち元気にしてる〜？
Assistants, how are you all doing?
ついてこなきゃ後悔だよ〜！ハイ！
You'll regret it if you don't follow along! Yes!
足踏みかけない　だけど不可思議じゃない？
そんな瞬間 1, 2, 3 始めちゃわない？
Don't hesitate, but isn't it mysterious?
Shall we start that moment, 1, 2, 3?
常に Try! いざ Error!? 平気次はきっと Fine!
盛りだくさんな Day もういっちょ！
Always Try! Now Error!? It's fine, next will surely be Fine!
A day full of things, one more time!
ピックアップした謎解きの
Hidden on the other side
向こう側に隠れた…命題！
of the picked-up mystery... Proposition!
見逃したらもったいない
It's a waste if you miss it
冒険！正解！急いで Are you OK? いそげー！！
Adventure! Correct answer! Hurry, are you OK? Hurry up!!
いっせーのせ！未来どんどん進みましょう
One, two, go! Let's keep moving forward into the future,
僕らに限界はないから
because there are no limits for us
何か一つ　叶えてしまっても
Even if one thing is fulfilled,
大丈夫　ほら次がある
it's okay, look, there's a next one
飛んで　跳ねて　わおーん
Flying, jumping, wa-on
いつだって行動原理はね
my principle of action is always,
その胸に魔法を届けてしまいたい
I want to deliver magic to your heart,
ヨロコビのために！
for the sake of joy!
アイムコヨーテ！
I'm Coyote!
かわいーですとやー！
I'm cute, ta-da!
どや！
Doya!
いつもどっちに行ったら正解なのかは
実はとっても難しいけれど
Actually, it's very difficult to know
which way is the correct one to go,
だからこそです　迷った時には
笑顔だけを　見つめます
That's why when I'm lost,
I'll only look at the smiles
あっち　こっち　ほら巻き起こる
Over there, over here, look, a drama unfolds,
ドラマに体当たり…実験！
diving in headfirst... Experiment!
感じて、そして始めましょう
Feel it, and then let's begin
研究！生成！余裕で Are you OK?
Research! Creation! Easily, are you OK?
一緒にどんどん過ごしましょう
Let's spend more and more time together
あなたと経験していきたい
I want to experience things with you
全部の夢そろえて証明完了ーQ.E.D.ー
Gather all our dreams, proof complete -Q.E.D.-
泣いて 笑って Wow
Crying, laughing, wow
どんな日も永遠 願わくばスマイル
Every day, forever, wishing for a smile
その胸に芽生えて欲しいシアワセ
I want happiness to sprout in that heart
今(ゼッタイ)以上(史上)最大のテーマ
The biggest theme ever (absolutely) right now
さあ(さあ)もっと(ずっと)Happy叶えましょう
Come on (come on), let's make even more (forever) happiness come true
助手くんたち準備はいいですか?
Joshu-kuns, are you ready?
まだまだたくさん証明していくからね〜!
I'm going to keep proving so much more!
あっぱれ!
Splendid!
はーい!ということで、博衣こより生誕ライブ2023「Memories」お楽しみいただきありがとうございました!
Hi! And with that, thank you for enjoying Hakui Koyori's Birthday Live 2023 "Memories"!
この後のエンディングでゲストの皆さんとのプチトークもありますので、最後まで見ていってくださいね!
There will be a mini talk with the guests during the ending, so please watch until the very end!
ということで、ここで大事なお知らせをさせてください!
So, I have some important announcements to make!
まず一つ目は、今歌った新曲「史上最大のQUESTION!」は、すでに本日の0時からデジタル販売開始されております!
First, the new song I just sang, "Shijou Saidai no QUESTION!", has already been available for digital purchase since midnight today!
概要欄から飛べますので、ぜひ、さっきの「エゴイスティック・シーソー」と合わせてゲットしてください!
You can access it from the description, so please get it along with "Egoistic Seesaw" from earlier!
そして二つ目!博衣こより誕生日グッズ2023が発売されます!
And second! Hakui Koyori Birthday Goods 2023 are going on sale!
一つ目は、お待たせいたしました!ラバーマット&カードスリーブのセット!
The first one, thanks for waiting! It's a rubber mat and card sleeve set!
パソコン周りで使うもよし、カードゲームでプレイする時のマットにするもよし!
You can use it around your computer or as a mat when playing card games!
イラストはあの、こよの推しのイラストなども手掛けていらっしゃる霧崎先生にお描きいただきました!
The illustration was drawn by Kirisaki-sensei, who also works on illustrations of Koyo's favorites!
カードゲーム好きとしては絶対欲しかったスリーブも付けちゃったよ!お気に入りのカード入れてください!
As a card game lover, I even included sleeves which I absolutely wanted! Please put your favorite cards in them!
そして、ライブの思い出を飾れるキャンバスアート!
And, canvas art to decorate your memories of the live!
イラストは北田藻先生描き下ろしです!
The illustration is newly drawn by Kitada Mo-sensei!
すっごくエモくて元気あふれる1枚に仕上げていただきました!おうちに飾ったら見るたびにこよとの思い出を振り返ってエモくなれること間違いなし!
It's been finished as a very emotional and energetic piece! If you display it at home, you'll definitely feel emotional every time you look at it and remember your memories with Koyo!
さらに!お待たせしました!助手くん証明書!
Furthermore! Thanks for waiting! A Joshu-kun certificate!
エコよラボの社員証みたいな、めっちゃしっかりした材質の証明書になっています!
It's a certificate made of a very sturdy material, like an Ecoyo Lab employee ID!
あなただけのナンバリング入りで、名前も書けちゃう!
It comes with your very own numbering, and you can even write your name on it!
裏面は、お財布に入れたりしてちらっと見えた時にハッピーになれる、北田先生の描き下ろしイラスト入りで、こよの手書きメッセージとサインも入ってますよ!
On the back, there's a newly drawn illustration by Kitada-sensei that'll make you happy when you catch a glimpse of it in your wallet, along with a handwritten message and signature from Koyo!
そして、お誕生日を一緒に過ごせるシチュエーションボイスも販売します!
And, we're also selling a situation voice where we can spend my birthday together!
全部セットには、なんと特典が二つ!
The full set comes with two special perks!
一つ目は、博衣こよりオリジナルのサイン入りのカードです!
The first one is an original Hakui Koyori card with a signature!
限定数でごめんね!直筆サインを入れさせていただきます!みんなに行き渡るくらいには書く予定なんですけれども、お早めにお願いします!
Sorry it's a limited quantity! I'll be hand-signing them! I plan to write enough for everyone to get one, but please be quick!
ぜひゲットして、こよのカードスリーブに入れてください!
Please get it and put it in Koyo's card sleeve!
二つ目は、こよが逆に助手くんのお誕生日を祝っちゃうASMRボイス!
The second one is an ASMR voice where Koyo conversely celebrates Joshu-kun's birthday!
こよも助手くんのことお祝いしたかったんだ〜!ゲットしておいて、自分の誕生日に聴いてくださいね!
Koyo wanted to celebrate Joshu-kun too! Please get it and listen to it on your own birthday!
もちろん今回も今年の誕生日限定のグッズです!この機会を逃すとゲットできなくなっちゃうので、絶対にゲットしてください!
Of course, these are goods limited to this year's birthday again! If you miss this chance, you won't be able to get them, so please make sure to get them!
以上、お知らせでしたー!
That's all for the announcements!
ということで、生誕祭来てくれてありがとう。
So, thank you for coming to my birthday celebration.
いつもたくさんの思い出をありがとう。
Thank you for always giving me so many memories.
助手くん、大好きだよ。んーっ、ま!
Joshu-kun, I love you. Mwah!
せーの、こよりお誕生日おめでとう! ありがとうございます! イェーイ!
One, two... Happy birthday, Koyori! Thank you! Yay!
3人でこのStart Dashを踊れてよかった! 本当にこよも嬉しかったです!
I'm glad the three of us could dance 'Start Dash'! I was really happy too!
あのさ、すごいなんかさ、声めっちゃ合ってたよね? 初めてだったけど、よかったですよねー!
You know, our voices blended really well, didn't they? It was our first time, but it was great!
いやーよかった。もうこの3人でまた何かやるしかない! 歌ったり踊ったりしましょう!
It was. We have no choice but to do something with the three of us again! Let's sing and dance!
あそぼうぜ! オッケー! ありがとう、こよりおめでとう!
Let's play! Okay! Thank you, congrats Koyori!
メルちゃん、ノエル先輩、お風呂含めいっぱい遊んでくれてありがとうございました!
Mel-chan, Noel-senpai, thank you for playing with me so much, including the bath!
こよちゃん、また一緒にお風呂入ろうね。 タプタプ
Koyo-chan, let's take a bath together again. *Splosh splosh*
汗かいたし、今入っちゃうか。 え? いいんですか? え、きゃー!
Since we're all sweaty, shall we go now? Eh? Is it okay? Eh, kyaa!
うぎゅう〜!
Huuuug!
ミオ先輩、つぼ押し、フブキ先輩、ホラー見守りありがとうございました!
Mio-senpai, for the massage, and Fubuki-senpai, for watching over the horror, thank you so much!
うんうん、次は金つぼだね、楽しみだね。 あ、あ、は、はい!
Yeah, yeah, next is the golden pressure point, looking forward to it. A-Ah, y-yes!
湯治に入っても大丈夫だから、これからもホラー頑張ってね。
It's okay to go for hot spring treatment, so keep doing your best with horror.
精一杯頑張ります！
I'll do my absolute best!
頑張ろう頑張ろう！
Let's do it! Let's do it!
こよりん、誕生日おめでとうだ！
Koyorin, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
やー、デュエットライブは初めてだったけど、
Man, it was our first duet live,
クロたんの愛が伝わってきたよ！
but I could feel Kuro-tan's love!
え？なんか韻も踏んでます？
Huh? Are you rhyming, too?
え？え？え？
What? What? What?
こっちは誕生日やぞおい！
Hey, it's my birthday over here!
はい誕生日おめでとう。じゃあね、こよこよ！
Yes, happy birthday. See ya, Koyokoyo!
なー、こよこよだ！
Hey, she called me Koyokoyo!
おめでとう、こよ。
Happy birthday, Koyo.
はい、あの、
Yes, um,
こよとトワ様ってマブってことでいいですかね？
is it okay to say Koyo and Towa-sama are besties?
え？え？
Eh? Eh?
さすがにそろそろ...
It's probably about time...
マブで...
Besties...
マブでしょ！
We're besties!
ないよね！
No way!
なんで今いい感じだったじゃん！
Why? It was a good moment just now!
いや、でもほら、ここでマブって言っちゃうと、
No, but look, if I say we're besties here,
振りがさ、トワに絡むときにさ、
the setup... when you mess with me,
「え、マブでしょ？」の絡みができなくなるかなと思って。
I won't be able to do the "Wait, aren't we besties?" bit anymore.
なるほど。
I see.
そうそうそう、
Right, right, right,
いっぱいこよに、これからも絡んでほしいってことですね！
you mean you want to keep messing with Koyo a lot!
あ、今日も誕生日おめでとう！
Ah, happy birthday today, too!
え？ちょっと、何で逃げるの？
Eh? Hey, why are you running away?
あ、リリスちゃん...
Ah, Ririsu-chan...
開けてもらえなかったね。
We couldn't get it opened, huh?
本当ですよ。
Seriously.
あれ？こよ一人だったら開けてもらえたかな？
Wait, would they have opened it if Koyo was alone?
はっ！
Ha!
はっ、マリ一人だったら...
Ha, if it was just Mari...
開けてもらえたのになあ。
they would've opened it.
この曲、あの、開けてもらえてないじゃないですか。
For this song, you know, it hasn't been opened.
さすが知能、負けました。論破されてしまいました。
As expected of the intellect, I lost. I've been logic-ed.
ズナン！
Zunan!
まあ、でもこんなに金銀財宝あれば、
Well, but with all this gold and treasure,
二人ぼっちでも楽しいっすよ。
even just the two of us is fun.
確かに！そうだよね、こよ。誕生日おめでとう！
True! That's right, Koyo. Happy birthday!
ここで暮らしましょう！
Let's live here!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so much!
ずっと一緒だよ！
We'll be together forever!
わーい！
Yay!
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING
生誕祭LIVE！みてくれてありがとう！
Birthday LIVE! Thanks for watching!
みんなにお祝いしてもらって最高の誕生日になったよ
Getting to celebrate with everyone made it the best birthday ever.
ハッシュタグで感想がいっぱいこれたら嬉しいな♡みにいくね！！
I'd be happy if I got lots of feedback via the hashtag! I'll go check them!!
また1年いっしょに楽しんで、来年もこの場所で会おう！！
Let's have fun together for another year, and meet again in this place next year!!